<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HOT-PDC Training Site</title>
    <link>/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on HOT-PDC Training Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating and Managing Tasking Manager</title>
      <link>/en/pages/02-hot-tasking-manager/01-membuat-dan-mengelola-tasking-manager/01_membuat_dan_mengelola_tasking_manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/02-hot-tasking-manager/01-membuat-dan-mengelola-tasking-manager/01_membuat_dan_mengelola_tasking_manager/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Explain the functions of Tasking Manager in the context of participatory mapping
 Able to explain how to make Tasking Manager
 Able to explain how to manage existing Tasking Manager
  You must already know how to use tasking manager to perform mapping activities together. When you use a tasking manager that doesn&amp;rsquo;t suit the area you want, then you might want to make a tasking manager for your own area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Collection Methodology</title>
      <link>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/01-metodologi-pengumpulan-data/01_metodologi_pengumpulan_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/01-metodologi-pengumpulan-data/01_metodologi_pengumpulan_data/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Understand Data Collection Preparation Understand Data Collection Workflow Knowing Tools that used in Data Collection Understand How to Collect Data in the Field  Data collecting or commonly known as field survey is an important aspect in mapping activity especially in disaster management. Even though technology advancement nowadays such as aerial and satellite imagery is capable to help us to map remotely, there are some information that only can get by going to the mapping area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Download OSM Data using Export Tool</title>
      <link>/en/pages/05-hot-export/01-penggunaan-export-tool/01_menggunakan_export_tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/05-hot-export/01-penggunaan-export-tool/01_menggunakan_export_tool/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to explain the definition and function of Export Tools To be able to operate Export Tools  In this chapter, we can learn about how to download the OSM data that we have added and uploaded into OSM. The data can be used to analysis, customize with data symbology, create maps, and others depend on your necessary.
I. Export Tool Concept The Export Tool is an open service that creates customized extracts of up-to-date OSM data in various file formats, such as ESRI shapefiles (.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to OpenStreetMap</title>
      <link>/en/pages/03-josm/01-pengenalan-osm/01_pengenalan_osm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/03-josm/01-pengenalan-osm/01_pengenalan_osm/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to explain what OpenStreetMap is To be able to explain the history of OpenStreetMap To be able to explain the benefits of using OpenStreetMap To be able to explain the use of OpenStreetMap To be able to explain the basic concept of map and OpenStreetMap  Nowadays a lot of people use digital map, but only a few use open source digital map. Open source digital map is totally free and editable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStreetMap Data Integration to InAWARE</title>
      <link>/en/pages/08-osm-data-integration-to-inaware/01-integrasi-osm-ke-inaware/01_integrasi_data_osm_ke_inaware/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/08-osm-data-integration-to-inaware/01-integrasi-osm-ke-inaware/01_integrasi_data_osm_ke_inaware/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Knowing to create an account in InAWARE Knowing Add OpenStreetMap Data into InAWARE  The main goal of HOT-PDC InAWARE Mapping Project is to to complete and provide spatial open data for public so it can be used for any disaster management sector by National Government (BNPB) and Local Disaster Management Agency (BPBD) in InAWARE, a platform that made by Pacific Disaster Center (PDC), an institution from University of Hawaii.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quality Assurance Concept</title>
      <link>/en/pages/04-data-validation-and-quality-assurance/01-konsep-penjaminan-kualitas/01_konsep_penjaminan_kualitas/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/04-data-validation-and-quality-assurance/01-konsep-penjaminan-kualitas/01_konsep_penjaminan_kualitas/</guid>
      <description>Learning Objectives:
 Understanding the definition of quality assurance Understanding the meaning of data quality assurance in OpenStreetMap  OpenStreetMap (OSM) is a free and open source map. OSM has a lot of data and information about various types of objects that exist on the surface of the earth. The data is collected and entered by OSM users spread all over the world. The variety of data entered and collected by OSM users often results in the quality of the data being different from one another and the lack of understanding of OSM users regarding data quality also affects the results of data available in OSM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mapping Methodology with OpenStreetMap</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/01-metodologi-kerangka-kerja-pemetaan-openstreetmap/01_metodologi_kerangka_kerja_pemetaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/01-metodologi-kerangka-kerja-pemetaan-openstreetmap/01_metodologi_kerangka_kerja_pemetaan/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to explain how to create a timeline for mapping activity To be able to explain how to create a folder for each team mapping To be able to explain how to divide the survey area based on the administrative boundary To be able to explain how to create team mapping effectively  Planning a mapping project requires an appropriate and efficient survey methodology to achieve the target and purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with OpenStreetMap</title>
      <link>/en/pages/03-josm/02-memulai-menggunakan-openstreetmap/02_memulai_menggunakan_openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/03-josm/02-memulai-menggunakan-openstreetmap/02_memulai_menggunakan_openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>Objective:
 To be able to operate and navigate the OpenStreetMap website To be able to see object information in OpenStreetMap To be able to create share link in OpenStreetMap To be able to save images from OpenStreetMap To be able to create user account in OpenStreetMap To be able to understand the basic concept of attribute in OpenStreetMap To be able to understand history in OpenStreetMap  After you understand the basic of OpenStreetMap in the previous module, you can immediately start using OpenStreetMap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JOSM for Validating Survey Data</title>
      <link>/en/pages/04-data-validation-and-quality-assurance/02-penggunaan-josm-untuk-validasi-data-survei/josm-for-validating-survey-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/04-data-validation-and-quality-assurance/02-penggunaan-josm-untuk-validasi-data-survei/josm-for-validating-survey-data/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To do initial checking on field survey data using JOSM To do a quality assurance on field survey data using JOSM To understand the type of error and warning on JOSM  JOSM is a software that has a function to do mapping and editing in OpenStreetMap. Why JOSM? Because JOSM has many functions to support your mapping and editing in OpenStreetMap. One of the features is its capability of doing data validation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStreetMap Data Model</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/02-model-data-openstreetmap/02_model_data_openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/02-model-data-openstreetmap/02_model_data_openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Understanding Concept of tag, key, dan value in OpenStreetMap Knowing OpenStreetMap wiki page as a guideline for key and value Understanding Objects which can be mapped into OpenStreetMap Knowing and Understanding data model as a part of mapping preparation plan Checking specific key and value in TagInfo website  In this module, you will learn about key and value concept in OpenStreetMap (OSM) as well as data model in OSM objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ODK Collect</title>
      <link>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/02-menggunakan-aplikasi-odk-collect/02_menggunakan_aplikasi_odk_collect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/02-menggunakan-aplikasi-odk-collect/02_menggunakan_aplikasi_odk_collect/</guid>
      <description>Objective:
 Able to explain ODK Collect as one of the tools to collect infrastructure data Able to set the initial setup for ODK Collect Able to apply how to use ODK Collect for data collection survey  I. What is ODK Collect? Open Data Kit Collect (ODK Collect) is a data collection application on Android. ODK Collect can replace form survey from paper to digital. Therefore, this application will help the mapping and data collection activities in the field which also allow to save the location and photo information at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Tasking Manager</title>
      <link>/en/pages/02-hot-tasking-manager/02-penggunaan-tasking-manager/02_penggunaan_tasking_manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/02-hot-tasking-manager/02-penggunaan-tasking-manager/02_penggunaan_tasking_manager/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Using functions of tasking manager for participatory mapping Operating tasking manager for mapping  As an alternative for open source mapping platform, OpenStreetMap allows everyone to do mapping anytime, anywhere. The problem is, what if you want to do mapping along with the other mapper on the same time? Tasking Manager allows you to divide an area of mapping so everyone can do mapping together. In this module, you will learn more detail about Tasking Manager and how to mapping using Tasking Manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Presets</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/03-membuat-presets-openstreetmap/03_membuat_presets_openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/03-membuat-presets-openstreetmap/03_membuat_presets_openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to comprehend presets concept on OpenStreetMap To be able to comprehend XML format to create presets on OpenStreetMap To be able to create a customized presets on OpenStreetMap To be able to comprehend presets elements  As explained before, OpenStreetMap is a free, open, participatory map of the whole world. This means that the use of OpenStreetMap can be very distinctive. The more distinct the mapping objectives are, the more diverse the information are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Quality Assurance with Tasking Manager</title>
      <link>/en/pages/04-data-validation-and-quality-assurance/03-penjaminan-kualitas-data-dengan-tasking-manager/03_penjaminan_kualitas_data_dengan_tasking_manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/04-data-validation-and-quality-assurance/03-penjaminan-kualitas-data-dengan-tasking-manager/03_penjaminan_kualitas_data_dengan_tasking_manager/</guid>
      <description>Objective:
 Understand data quality assurance by using tasking manager  Previously you have edited OpenStreetMap data using tasking manager. Tasking manager make you easier to edit OpenStreetMap data without have to worry about conflict with other people because you are working in the same area. Beside for edit OpenStreetMap data, you can also validate using the tasking manager, so you and the others can do validation together at the same time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Java OpenStreetMap (JOSM)</title>
      <link>/en/pages/03-josm/03-pengenalan-java-openstreetmap-josm/03_pengenalan_java_openstreetmap_josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/03-josm/03-pengenalan-java-openstreetmap-josm/03_pengenalan_java_openstreetmap_josm/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Understand how to download JOSM installation file Able to install JOSM Able to change JOSM settings Understand JOSM interface  Java OpenStreetMap (JOSM) is a OpenStreetMap desktop-based editor. JOSM allows you to edit the mapping data in offline mode for some time, so you don’t always need to connect to the internet. It will certainly make it easier for everyone who works within limited internet connections. You only need an internet connection when downloading data from OpenStreetMap and when uploading data to OpenStreetMap server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the OpenMapKit Application</title>
      <link>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/03-menggunakan-aplikasi-omk/03_menggunakan_aplikasi_omk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/03-menggunakan-aplikasi-omk/03_menggunakan_aplikasi_omk/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Able to explain OpenMapkit as one of the tools for collecting infrastructure data Able to operate the initial setup for OpenMapKit Able to operate how to enter offline basemap for OpenMapKit Able to operate OpenMapKit  Previously you already learn the ODK (OpenDataKit) Collect, an android-based application to replace paper form for surveys. ODK Collect has extension called OpenMapKit (OMK). This extension is used to add information on the position or location of the object surveyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JOSM for Data Quality</title>
      <link>/en/pages/04-data-validation-and-quality-assurance/04-josm-untuk-perhitungan-kualitas-data/04_josm_perhitungan_kualitas_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/04-data-validation-and-quality-assurance/04-josm-untuk-perhitungan-kualitas-data/04_josm_perhitungan_kualitas_data/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Understanding how to select and count numbers of objects in certain administration boundary Understanding how to count numbers of error and warning in certain administration boundary Understanding how to validate administration boundary  One of the expected results in doing mapping activity is to produce a good quality map. The quality including object information completeness and right topology. Using OpenStreetMap as a base map to show the result of field survey could help you to monitor the progress of your mapping activity result by counting objects and information from the field.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Java OpenStreetMap (JOSM)</title>
      <link>/en/pages/03-josm/04-menggunakan-java-openstreetmap-josm/04_menggunakan_java_openstreetmap_josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/03-josm/04-menggunakan-java-openstreetmap-josm/04_menggunakan_java_openstreetmap_josm/</guid>
      <description>Objective:
 Understanding how to use basic tools in JOSM Able to operate advance editing in JOSM Understanding editing tips in JOSM Understanding how to draw special objects such as bridge, school, and road networks  Java OpenStreetMap or commonly called JOSM is a desktop-based editor for OpenStreetMap. JOSM allows you to edit OSM data offline for a while or not always connect to the internet. If in the previous module you learned about operating JOSM, then in this module you will learn how to use JOSM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OSMTrackers</title>
      <link>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/04-menggunakan-aplikasi-osmtracker/04_menggunakan_aplikasi_osmtracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/04-menggunakan-aplikasi-osmtracker/04_menggunakan_aplikasi_osmtracker/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Explain OSMTracker as one of survey tools for recording tracks and photos
 How to set up the OSMTracker for the first time
 Learn how to use OSMTracker
  I. What is OSMTracker? OSMTracker is an android application that allows us to record our survey data. Similar to GPS, OSMTracker is able to record waypoint and also track. If you want to learn more about GPS for field survey, you can see the GPS Module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using YAML</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/04-penggunaan-yaml-pada-export-tool/04-penggunaan-yaml-pada-export-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/04-penggunaan-yaml-pada-export-tool/04-penggunaan-yaml-pada-export-tool/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to explain about YAML concept To be able to create YAML for export data in Export Tool To be able to demonstrate how to get OSM data in Export Tool using YAML  As explained before, we have learned how to create a customized presets on OpenStreetMap and determine the OpenStreetMap data model to use in the mapping process. In the chapter Using Export Tool, we found the result data attributes only show the attribute from the OSM format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Survey Data into OSM Using JOSM</title>
      <link>/en/pages/03-josm/05-menambahkan-data-osm-menggunakan-josm/05_menambahkan_data_osm_menggunakan_josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/03-josm/05-menambahkan-data-osm-menggunakan-josm/05_menambahkan_data_osm_menggunakan_josm/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to install plugin Utilsplugin2 To be able to merge all survey data To be able to save .osm file using JOSM To be able to download OSM data To be able to add satellite imagery layer on JOSM To be able to add and edit OSM data using JOSM To be able to upload changes into OSM To be able to view changes of OSM data in OSM website  Adding or mapping new objects in OSM is one way to enrich OSM data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating survey form for ODK Collect &amp; OpenMapKit</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/05-membuat-formulir-survei-untuk-aplikasi-odk-collect-openmapkit/05_membuat_formulir_survei_untuk_aplikasi_odk_collect__openmapkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/05-membuat-formulir-survei-untuk-aplikasi-odk-collect-openmapkit/05_membuat_formulir_survei_untuk_aplikasi_odk_collect__openmapkit/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Explain the concept of XLSForm Operate the creation of an XLSForm for ODK Collect Operate the creation of an XLSForm for OpenMapKit  In field survey activities sometimes you need a survey form to collect the data. Imagine if you need a form survey with dozens of questions for each respondent, you will certainly experience difficulties when filling data and also when entering data into a laptop. In this material you will learn how to create a survey form in digital format which will later be entered into your mobile phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GPS</title>
      <link>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/05-menggunakan-gps/05_menggunakan_gps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/05-menggunakan-gps/05_menggunakan_gps/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Understand parts of GPS Understand how to turn on GPS Understand how to use GPS Understand definition of track and waypoint in GPS Understand how to turn on track in GPS Understand how to save waypoint in GPS Understand how to copy track and waypoint to computer  When doing a field survey, a navigation tool that has a function to record track and point is needed. Global Positioning Syste or GPS is frequently used tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload survey form to ona.io</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/06-meletakkan-form-survey-ke-ona.io/06_meletakkan_form_survey_ke_ona.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/06-meletakkan-form-survey-ke-ona.io/06_meletakkan_form_survey_ke_ona.io/</guid>
      <description>Learning Objectives:
 Able to explain the benefits of using Ona.io Explain how to upload survey forms to the Ona.io server  After we have successfully created the survey forms that have been studied in the module Making Survey Forms for the ODK Collect &amp;amp; OpenMapKit Application, You will learn the platform used to upload survey forms to one of the platforms. The platform used in this material are Ona.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using To-Do List in JOSM</title>
      <link>/en/pages/03-josm/06-menggunakan-to-do-list-di-josm/06_menggunakan_to_do_list_di_josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/03-josm/06-menggunakan-to-do-list-di-josm/06_menggunakan_to_do_list_di_josm/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to do plugin installation to input data in JOSM To be able to operate to-do list plugin in JOSM to input the data  After conducting a survey using the OpenMapKit (OMK) application, the next step you need to do is to input survey data as points in OpenStreetMap using JOSM. To make it easier for you to do that, you need to install JOSM plugin named Todo list plugin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Field Maps using QGIS</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/07-pembuatan-peta-survey-dengan-qgis/07-pembuatan-peta-survey-dengan-qgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/07-pembuatan-peta-survey-dengan-qgis/07-pembuatan-peta-survey-dengan-qgis/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to operate QGIS to install QuicMapServices Plugin To be able to operate QGIS to create a field survey map  Field maps are used to advise data entry in identifying the locations during the field survey. If data entries have gotten the administrative boundary with the government in the village office, a field map can be used to delineation the administrative boundary. Then we can bring the map to our office and input the boundary using JOSM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Filter on JOSM</title>
      <link>/en/pages/03-josm/07-menggunakan-alat-filter-di-josm/07_menggunakan_alat_filter_di_josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/03-josm/07-menggunakan-alat-filter-di-josm/07_menggunakan_alat_filter_di_josm/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to activate data filtering mode on JOSM To be able to operate a data filtering tool on JOSM  JOSM has many tools that can be used by the user to make mapping things easier, like a filter tool. Filter tool is an additional tool that allows you to select or shown only certain objects on JOSM based on key and value on OpenStreetMap. With these tools, you can edit or check specific data on OSM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating MBTiles for OpenMapKit (OMK)</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/08-pembuatan-mbtiles-untuk-openmapkit/08_membuat_mbtiles_untuk_openmapkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/08-pembuatan-mbtiles-untuk-openmapkit/08_membuat_mbtiles_untuk_openmapkit/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to understand the concept of MBTiles To be able to create MBTiles using Export Tool To be able to create MBTiles using Plugin QTiles To be able to add file MBTiles into OMK in smartphone  When you use the OpenMapKit (OMK) application to conduct field surveys, sometimes you will have difficulty in determining objects in the application. It may happen because the background map is not yet mapped in OpenStreetMap and you do not have time to digitize objects in the survey area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using buildings tools on JOSM</title>
      <link>/en/pages/03-josm/08-menggunakan-building-tools-di-josm/08_menggunakan_building_tools_di_josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/03-josm/08-menggunakan-building-tools-di-josm/08_menggunakan_building_tools_di_josm/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to install plugin for drawing buildings To be able to use JOSM plugin to draw buildings  When you map using JOSM without conducting field survey, the information mapped on OSM will be very limited since you only use satellite imagery as reference. One of the objects that can be mapped using satellite imagery as reference is building. However, you won’t be able to figure out the specific function of the mapped buildings unless the building has a unique shape such as an L-shaped or a U-shaped school building.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating the Administrative Boundaries in JOSM</title>
      <link>/en/pages/03-josm/09-pembuatan-batas-administrasi-dengan-josm/09.pembuatan_batas_administrasi_dengan_josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/03-josm/09-pembuatan-batas-administrasi-dengan-josm/09.pembuatan_batas_administrasi_dengan_josm/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to explain the definition and example of relation in OpenStreetMap To be able to explain administrative boundary concept in OpenStreetMap To be able to explain term and condition to create an administrative boundary in OpenStreetMap To be able to create the administrative boundaries in OpenStreetMap  The mapping of administrative boundaries in OpenStreetMap was suggested to an advanced mapper or experienced user with regularly mapping in OpenStreetMap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group Stats Plugin for Calculate The Objects</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/09-perhitungan-kuantitas-data-menggunakan-plugin-group-stats/09-perhitungan-kuantitas-data-menggunakan-plugin-group-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/09-perhitungan-kuantitas-data-menggunakan-plugin-group-stats/09-perhitungan-kuantitas-data-menggunakan-plugin-group-stats/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to demonstrate how to install a plugin for calculate number of object in QGIS To be able to operate the Group Stats plugin for calculate number of OSM Object  The calculation of the quantity of data can be an indicator of the achievement of mapping projects that can be poured into a mapping report. The process of calculating the quantity of OSM data can be done by installing the plugin group stats in QGIS for free, this plugin can use to count the number of objects based on categories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Shapefile Data to GeoJSON</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/10-konversi-data-shapefile-ke-geojson/10_konversi_data_shapefile_ke_geojson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/10-konversi-data-shapefile-ke-geojson/10_konversi_data_shapefile_ke_geojson/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to understand the definition of GeoJSON data To be able to convert shapefile to GeoJSON with QGIS To be able to download GeoJSON from Overpass Turbo To be able to convert shapefile to GeoJSON using GeoData Converter  If you do not have an educational background in geography or you are not too familiar with Geographic Information Systems (GIS), then this GeoJSON format may sound familiar to you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving Conflict on OpenStreetMap Data (OSM)</title>
      <link>/en/pages/03-josm/10-mengatasi-konflik-data-pada-openstreetmap/10_mengatasi_konflik_pada_data_openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/03-josm/10-mengatasi-konflik-data-pada-openstreetmap/10_mengatasi_konflik_pada_data_openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Participants can explain what is data conflict on OpenStreetMap Participants knowing about types of conflict in JOSM Participants can fix data conflicts using JOSM Participants know to avoid data conflict in JOSM  When you are uploading your changes in JSOM, some contributors might also do editing in your area. This might occur data conflict in your uploading process. Therefore, in this module, you will learn about data conflict in OpenStreetMap, types of conflict, and how to fix it using JOSM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Map Campaigner to Manage Mapping Campaign</title>
      <link>/en/pages/07-map-campaigner/01-membuat-dan-mengelola-map-campaigner-untuk-pemetaan/01_membuat_dan_mengelola_map_campaigner_untuk_pemetaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/07-map-campaigner/01-membuat-dan-mengelola-map-campaigner-untuk-pemetaan/01_membuat_dan_mengelola_map_campaigner_untuk_pemetaan/</guid>
      <description>Learning Objectives:
 Knowing and understanding how to work with Map Campaigners Operating Map Campaigners to create mapping activities Operate Map Campaigners to monitor mapping activities  In implementing a mapping project you often need a report regarding the progress of the activity in a statistical data about how many objects have been mapped in the activity. There are several tools that can be used to obtain statistical data. One of the tools that we will learn today is Map Campaigner.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>