<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>JOSM on HOT-PDC Training Site</title>
    <link>/en/pages/03-josm/</link>
    <description>Recent content in JOSM on HOT-PDC Training Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/en/pages/03-josm/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with OpenStreetMap</title>
      <link>/en/pages/03-josm/02-memulai-menggunakan-openstreetmap/02_memulai_menggunakan_openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/03-josm/02-memulai-menggunakan-openstreetmap/02_memulai_menggunakan_openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>Objective:
 To be able to operate and navigate the OpenStreetMap website To be able to see object information in OpenStreetMap To be able to create share link in OpenStreetMap To be able to save images from OpenStreetMap To be able to create user account in OpenStreetMap To be able to understand the basic concept of attribute in OpenStreetMap To be able to understand history in OpenStreetMap  After you understand the basic of OpenStreetMap in the previous module, you can immediately start using OpenStreetMap.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding Survey Data into OSM Using JOSM</title>
      <link>/en/pages/03-josm/05-menambahkan-data-osm-menggunakan-josm/05_menambahkan_data_osm_menggunakan_josm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/03-josm/05-menambahkan-data-osm-menggunakan-josm/05_menambahkan_data_osm_menggunakan_josm/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to install plugin Utilsplugin2 To be able to merge all survey data To be able to save .osm file using JOSM To be able to download OSM data To be able to add satellite imagery layer on JOSM To be able to add and edit OSM data using JOSM To be able to upload changes into OSM To be able to view changes of OSM data in OSM website  Adding or mapping new objects in OSM is one way to enrich OSM data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resolving Conflict on OpenStreetMap Data (OSM)</title>
      <link>/en/pages/03-josm/10-mengatasi-konflik-data-pada-openstreetmap/10_mengatasi_konflik_pada_data_openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/03-josm/10-mengatasi-konflik-data-pada-openstreetmap/10_mengatasi_konflik_pada_data_openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Participants can explain what is data conflict on OpenStreetMap Participants knowing about types of conflict in JOSM Participants can fix data conflicts using JOSM Participants know to avoid data conflict in JOSM  When you are uploading your changes in JSOM, some contributors might also do editing in your area. This might occur data conflict in your uploading process. Therefore, in this module, you will learn about data conflict in OpenStreetMap, types of conflict, and how to fix it using JOSM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>