<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenStreetMap Guide for Surveyor on HOT-PDC Training Site</title>
    <link>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in OpenStreetMap Guide for Surveyor on HOT-PDC Training Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Collection Methodology</title>
      <link>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/01-metodologi-pengumpulan-data/01_metodologi_pengumpulan_data/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/01-metodologi-pengumpulan-data/01_metodologi_pengumpulan_data/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Understand Data Collection Preparation Understand Data Collection Workflow Knowing Tools that used in Data Collection Understand How to Collect Data in the Field  Data collecting or commonly known as field survey is an important aspect in mapping activity especially in disaster management. Even though technology advancement nowadays such as aerial and satellite imagery is capable to help us to map remotely, there are some information that only can get by going to the mapping area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using ODK Collect</title>
      <link>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/02-menggunakan-aplikasi-odk-collect/02_menggunakan_aplikasi_odk_collect/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/02-menggunakan-aplikasi-odk-collect/02_menggunakan_aplikasi_odk_collect/</guid>
      <description>Objective:
 Able to explain ODK Collect as one of the tools to collect infrastructure data Able to set the initial setup for ODK Collect Able to apply how to use ODK Collect for data collection survey  I. What is ODK Collect? Open Data Kit Collect (ODK Collect) is a data collection application on Android. ODK Collect can replace form survey from paper to digital. Therefore, this application will help the mapping and data collection activities in the field which also allow to save the location and photo information at once.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the OpenMapKit Application</title>
      <link>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/03-menggunakan-aplikasi-omk/03_menggunakan_aplikasi_omk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/03-menggunakan-aplikasi-omk/03_menggunakan_aplikasi_omk/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Able to explain OpenMapkit as one of the tools for collecting infrastructure data Able to operate the initial setup for OpenMapKit Able to operate how to enter offline basemap for OpenMapKit Able to operate OpenMapKit  Previously you already learn the ODK (OpenDataKit) Collect, an android-based application to replace paper form for surveys. ODK Collect has extension called OpenMapKit (OMK). This extension is used to add information on the position or location of the object surveyed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OSMTrackers</title>
      <link>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/04-menggunakan-aplikasi-osmtracker/04_menggunakan_aplikasi_osmtracker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/04-menggunakan-aplikasi-osmtracker/04_menggunakan_aplikasi_osmtracker/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Explain OSMTracker as one of survey tools for recording tracks and photos
 How to set up the OSMTracker for the first time
 Learn how to use OSMTracker
  I. What is OSMTracker? OSMTracker is an android application that allows us to record our survey data. Similar to GPS, OSMTracker is able to record waypoint and also track. If you want to learn more about GPS for field survey, you can see the GPS Module.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using GPS</title>
      <link>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/05-menggunakan-gps/05_menggunakan_gps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/01-osm-field-surveyor-guideliness/05-menggunakan-gps/05_menggunakan_gps/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Understand parts of GPS Understand how to turn on GPS Understand how to use GPS Understand definition of track and waypoint in GPS Understand how to turn on track in GPS Understand how to save waypoint in GPS Understand how to copy track and waypoint to computer  When doing a field survey, a navigation tool that has a function to record track and point is needed. Global Positioning Syste or GPS is frequently used tool.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>