<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Field Mapping Project Guide for Project Manager on HOT-PDC Training Site</title>
    <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Field Mapping Project Guide for Project Manager on HOT-PDC Training Site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mapping Methodology with OpenStreetMap</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/01-metodologi-kerangka-kerja-pemetaan-openstreetmap/01_metodologi_kerangka_kerja_pemetaan/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/01-metodologi-kerangka-kerja-pemetaan-openstreetmap/01_metodologi_kerangka_kerja_pemetaan/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to explain how to create a timeline for mapping activity To be able to explain how to create a folder for each team mapping To be able to explain how to divide the survey area based on the administrative boundary To be able to explain how to create team mapping effectively  Planning a mapping project requires an appropriate and efficient survey methodology to achieve the target and purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenStreetMap Data Model</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/02-model-data-openstreetmap/02_model_data_openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/02-model-data-openstreetmap/02_model_data_openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Understanding Concept of tag, key, dan value in OpenStreetMap Knowing OpenStreetMap wiki page as a guideline for key and value Understanding Objects which can be mapped into OpenStreetMap Knowing and Understanding data model as a part of mapping preparation plan Checking specific key and value in TagInfo website  In this module, you will learn about key and value concept in OpenStreetMap (OSM) as well as data model in OSM objects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Presets</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/03-membuat-presets-openstreetmap/03_membuat_presets_openstreetmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/03-membuat-presets-openstreetmap/03_membuat_presets_openstreetmap/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to comprehend presets concept on OpenStreetMap To be able to comprehend XML format to create presets on OpenStreetMap To be able to create a customized presets on OpenStreetMap To be able to comprehend presets elements  As explained before, OpenStreetMap is a free, open, participatory map of the whole world. This means that the use of OpenStreetMap can be very distinctive. The more distinct the mapping objectives are, the more diverse the information are.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using YAML</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/04-penggunaan-yaml-pada-export-tool/04-penggunaan-yaml-pada-export-tool/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/04-penggunaan-yaml-pada-export-tool/04-penggunaan-yaml-pada-export-tool/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to explain about YAML concept To be able to create YAML for export data in Export Tool To be able to demonstrate how to get OSM data in Export Tool using YAML  As explained before, we have learned how to create a customized presets on OpenStreetMap and determine the OpenStreetMap data model to use in the mapping process. In the chapter Using Export Tool, we found the result data attributes only show the attribute from the OSM format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating survey form for ODK Collect &amp; OpenMapKit</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/05-membuat-formulir-survei-untuk-aplikasi-odk-collect-openmapkit/05_membuat_formulir_survei_untuk_aplikasi_odk_collect__openmapkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/05-membuat-formulir-survei-untuk-aplikasi-odk-collect-openmapkit/05_membuat_formulir_survei_untuk_aplikasi_odk_collect__openmapkit/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 Explain the concept of XLSForm Operate the creation of an XLSForm for ODK Collect Operate the creation of an XLSForm for OpenMapKit  In field survey activities sometimes you need a survey form to collect the data. Imagine if you need a form survey with dozens of questions for each respondent, you will certainly experience difficulties when filling data and also when entering data into a laptop. In this material you will learn how to create a survey form in digital format which will later be entered into your mobile phone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upload survey form to ona.io</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/06-meletakkan-form-survey-ke-ona.io/06_meletakkan_form_survey_ke_ona.io/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/06-meletakkan-form-survey-ke-ona.io/06_meletakkan_form_survey_ke_ona.io/</guid>
      <description>Learning Objectives:
 Able to explain the benefits of using Ona.io Explain how to upload survey forms to the Ona.io server  After we have successfully created the survey forms that have been studied in the module Making Survey Forms for the ODK Collect &amp;amp; OpenMapKit Application, You will learn the platform used to upload survey forms to one of the platforms. The platform used in this material are Ona.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Field Maps using QGIS</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/07-pembuatan-peta-survey-dengan-qgis/07-pembuatan-peta-survey-dengan-qgis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/07-pembuatan-peta-survey-dengan-qgis/07-pembuatan-peta-survey-dengan-qgis/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to operate QGIS to install QuicMapServices Plugin To be able to operate QGIS to create a field survey map  Field maps are used to advise data entry in identifying the locations during the field survey. If data entries have gotten the administrative boundary with the government in the village office, a field map can be used to delineation the administrative boundary. Then we can bring the map to our office and input the boundary using JOSM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating MBTiles for OpenMapKit (OMK)</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/08-pembuatan-mbtiles-untuk-openmapkit/08_membuat_mbtiles_untuk_openmapkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/08-pembuatan-mbtiles-untuk-openmapkit/08_membuat_mbtiles_untuk_openmapkit/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to understand the concept of MBTiles To be able to create MBTiles using Export Tool To be able to create MBTiles using Plugin QTiles To be able to add file MBTiles into OMK in smartphone  When you use the OpenMapKit (OMK) application to conduct field surveys, sometimes you will have difficulty in determining objects in the application. It may happen because the background map is not yet mapped in OpenStreetMap and you do not have time to digitize objects in the survey area.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Group Stats Plugin for Calculate The Objects</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/09-perhitungan-kuantitas-data-menggunakan-plugin-group-stats/09-perhitungan-kuantitas-data-menggunakan-plugin-group-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/09-perhitungan-kuantitas-data-menggunakan-plugin-group-stats/09-perhitungan-kuantitas-data-menggunakan-plugin-group-stats/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to demonstrate how to install a plugin for calculate number of object in QGIS To be able to operate the Group Stats plugin for calculate number of OSM Object  The calculation of the quantity of data can be an indicator of the achievement of mapping projects that can be poured into a mapping report. The process of calculating the quantity of OSM data can be done by installing the plugin group stats in QGIS for free, this plugin can use to count the number of objects based on categories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Converting Shapefile Data to GeoJSON</title>
      <link>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/10-konversi-data-shapefile-ke-geojson/10_konversi_data_shapefile_ke_geojson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/en/pages/06-osm-field-survey-manager-guidelines/10-konversi-data-shapefile-ke-geojson/10_konversi_data_shapefile_ke_geojson/</guid>
      <description>Objectives:
 To be able to understand the definition of GeoJSON data To be able to convert shapefile to GeoJSON with QGIS To be able to download GeoJSON from Overpass Turbo To be able to convert shapefile to GeoJSON using GeoData Converter  If you do not have an educational background in geography or you are not too familiar with Geographic Information Systems (GIS), then this GeoJSON format may sound familiar to you.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>